

# **Mohamed Feddad**

Software Engineer

Github - SourceForge - PyPI

NPM - Libraries - GMail

Fullstack software engineer and an Open-Source enthusiast. I'm very passionate about GNU/Linux, Python and JavaScript/TypeScript. I have about four years of experience working with variety of web stacks and supporting cross-platform software applications. I seek and enjoy working on tasks that are challenging and mentally stimulating to grow my experience and deliver awesome software to production. I've worked with small and large remote teams through out different industries: Insurance, Marketing, Point of sale and Queue management. I don't believe in "One size fits all" or "One web stack to rule them all"! I truly enjoy diving into new technologies and different web stacks to enrich my experience and have the ability to choose whichever tool is most fitting for a given task. I had the utmost pleasure of working with the following web stacks: I. Flask, SQLAlchemy and JQuery. II. WebPy, MySQL and KnockoutJS. III. Django, PostgreSQL and VueJS. IV. ExpressJS, FireStore and ReactJS.

#### Education:

- I. Bachelor of Software Engineering Limkokwing University ( 2014-2017 )
- II. Masters of Software Engineering Limkokwing University ( 2018-ongoing )

### Experience:

- I. Freelance: With the Saudi investment bank to develop front-end UI for a game show ( 2016/12-2017/02 )
- II. Internship: With Compos-DZ an Algerian POS solutions as a fullstack engineer ( 2017/03-2018/01 )
- III. Fulltime: With BriteCore an American insurance platform as a fullstack engineer ( 2018/11-2019/11 )
- IV. *Freelance*: With Nuvonia a Turkish agile marketing startup as a fullstack engineer ( 2019/12-ongoing )

#### Open-Source:

- I. FQM: Web based queue management system, built with Python Flask and JQuery ( Website ) ( Github )
- II. Safelock: Cross-platform files encryption desktop application built with PyQT5 ( Softpedia ) ( ZDNet )
- III. Flask-Minify: Flask web framework extension to minify HTML response ( Github ) ( PyPI )

## Experience in keywords:

```
Python3/2 - Django - Django-Rest-Framework - WebPy - Quart - Flask - Flask-SQLAlchemy - Jinja2 - PySide - PyQt - Gevent - Asyncio - Threading - PyCrypto - Python-ESCPOS - PyInstaller - BeautifulSoup - Unittest - PyTest - Selenium - SQLAlchemy - MySQL - PostgreSQL - SQLite3 - SQLCipher - MangoDB - Redis - ES5-9 - TypeScript - jQuery - jQueryUI - KnockoutJS - Less - Sass - Bootstrap - NodeJS - ExpressJS - WebpackJS - BabelJS - VueyS - Vuex - VueRouter - ElementUI - ReactJS - Redux - ReactRedux - ReduxSaga - ReactBootstrap - ReactRouter - Jest - Mocha - GNU/Linux - Bash Script - Batch Script - Docker - Docker-Compose - AWS - EC2 - Lambda - AWS CodeBuild - FireBase - FireStore - Cloud Functions - Github Actions - Jenkins - Travis-CI - Jira - Agile
```